<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Human</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="">Emily Sullivan</author>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="race-chao-human.xml" url="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xyj7ukwg63t5vso/race-chao-human.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

  <element name="Chao Human" type="Race Variant" source="Sullivans Campaign" id="ID_SULLIVANS_RACE_VARIANT_CHAO_HUMAN">
    <supports>Human</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The people of Chao are human. Nearly all adults stand over six feet tall, and heights above seven feet are not uncommon. They are massively muscled and have gray skin, ranging from an ashy gray-white to a deeper bluegray. The typical chao’s hairline points sharply down in the middle of the forehead and at either temple, but recedes elsewhere—sometimes dramatically. chaos are remarkably resistant to the cold of their homeland, baring skin even in near-freezing temperatures without discomfort.</p>
      <p>chaos value self-reliance, strength, and courage above all else. Anything that is the product of their own labor is a fine thing. Anything else is treated with a healthy dose of skepticism. At best, they are a proud, pragmatic, passionate people, and their loyalty is fierce once earned. At worst, they can be reckless, hot-tempered, and violent—and no small number of chaos still consider these qualities virtues rather than vices.</p>
      <p>Because of their many exploits as both conquerors and mercenaries, chaos appear in the legends and histories of other peoples across the world. Sometimes these tales are exaggerated—but many that sound exaggerated are not.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span> Your dexterity score increases by 2.<br />
        <span class="feature">Age. </span>chaos reach adulthood in their late teens and live less than a century. <br />
        <span class="feature">Size. </span>chaos are taller and heavier than the human norms of other cultures, standing almost universally above 5' 5" feet tall and reaching heights above 6' feet. Your size is Medium.<br />
        <span class="feature">Speed. </span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
        <span class="feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Chao and 1 language of choice.<br />
		<span class="feature">Gift of Art. </span>You are proficient in Thieves Tools, Disguise Kit, or Painter Supplies.<br />
		<span class="feature">Gift of Ink. </span>You are proficient in Forgery Kit or Caligrapher's Supplies.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Grants" id="ID_RACE_VARIANT_HUMAN_VARIANT" />
      <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
	  <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_SULLIVANS_LANGUAGE_CHAO" />
	  <select type="Language" name="Language (Human)" supports="Standard||Exotic" requirements="!ID_UA_PS_GRANTS_HUMAN_VARIANT,!ID_WOTC_ERLW_DRAGONMARK_MARK_OF_FINDING"/>
	  <select type="Proficiency" name="Gift of Art" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_PAINTERS_SUPPLIES" />
	  <select type="Proficiency" name="Gift of Ink" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORGERY_KIT|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- Languages -->
  <element name="Chao" type="Language" source="Sullivans Campaign" id="ID_SULLIVANS_LANGUAGE_CHAO">
        <description>
            <p>A language common to the land of Erinos used mostly by the Chao Humans.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="standard">true</set>
            <set name="speakers">Humans</set>
            <set name="script">Humans</set>
        </setters>
   </element>



  
  
</elements>